Keith Marshall Collection of Photographs
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Places, Series II
  - Mauritius
    - Unidentified main road, Port Louis (?), 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photograph is unsigned, but found with stack labeled "Alex. Rambert photos." Depicts a dirt road running down the main section of a town, perhaps Pout Louis.
      Photographs; Mauritius; Port Louis (Mauritius)
    - Unidentified series of waterfalls, Mauritius (?), 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 15.5. x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse. Depicts a large series of waterfalls in a wooded valley, presumably in Mauritius.
    - Lake at Le Reduit, 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.7 x 21.4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photograph of a lake, probably at Le Reduit, Mauritius. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Le Lac Le Reduit, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a lake surrounded by lush vegetation. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
      Photographs; Mauritius
    - French Gardens, Le Reduit, 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21.5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Photograph depicting lush vegetation with a lake at the center. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Verandah of Reduit, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.7 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Unidentified building, Le Reduit (?), 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.7 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a large complex with two house-like units on either side of a covered walkway, which lies over a pillared verandah, likely that pictured in the image entitled "Verandah of Reduit." Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Labourdonnais Square, Port Louis, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.7 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts Labourdonnais Square, Port Louis, Mauritius, looking out towards the harbor, in which many tall-masted ships are seen. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
      Port Louis (Mauritius); Photographs; Mauritius
    - Rodrigue Palms, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      It depicts a long avenue of tall palm trees, in Mauritius. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Travellers Trees, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a grove of trees with a grass-roofed gazebo or hut at left. Several local people are seen by the gazebo and one small boy stands on the right bank of a small lake or other body of water. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Botanical Gardens, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a long avenue on the sides of which grow heavy clusters of palms and other vegetation. Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
    - Unidentified shoreline, two men and child in a boat, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Two men use long poles to guide a small boat towards a rocky shoreline. Presumably in Mauritius.
    - Unidentified avenue, Port Louis (?), 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a long dirt avenue with large stone and iron fences on either side. Probably in Port Louis, Mauritius.
      Mauritius; Port Louis (Mauritius); Photographs
    - Unidentified race or festival, Mauritius, 1880s or 1890s; Rambert, Alex; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Depicts a large grassy field covered with people, who seem to be attending a kind of festival or race (a track rings the field). Has the ink stamp of "Alex. Rambert" on the reverse.
  - Swartberg Pass, South Africa
    - Zwartberg Pass, Prince Albert, Oudtshoorn Road, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph; 28.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Depicts a large craggy pass, with a woman or girl in Western dress standing on a dirt road running through it. Has the ink stamp of "T.D. Ravenscroft" of Rondebosch (Cape Town), on the reverse.
      Swartberg Pass (South Africa); South Africa; Photographs; Landscape photographs
    - Zwartberg, Prince Albert, Oudtshoorn Road, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph; 28.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Depicts a clearing in a rocky mountain pass, with a horse and buggy on a dirt road. Has the ink stamp of "T.D. Ravenscroft" of Rondebosch (Cape Town), on the reverse.
      Swartberg Pass (South Africa); Photographs; South Africa; Landscape photographs
    - Zwartberg, Prince Albert, Oudtshoorn, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph; 21.5 x 28.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Depicts dirt roads running through a valley. Has the ink stamp of "T.D. Ravenscroft" of Rondebosch (Cape Town), on the reverse.
      Photographs; South Africa; Landscape photographs; Swartberg Pass (South Africa)
    - Zwart Berg Pass, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph; 28.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Depicts a craggy rock pass with a body of water in the foreground. A man with a horse and buggy are at water's edge on the opposite bank from the photographer. Has the ink stamp of "T.D. Ravenscroft" of Rondebosch (Cape Town), on the reverse.
  - South Africa
    - View of road and cliffs, South Africa, 1890s; Territorial Studio (Umtata, South Africa); 1 photograph; 14 x 20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Has, on the reverse, the ink stamp of the Territorial Studio (Umtata).
      South Africa; Photographs
    - Needles Hotel, Port St. Johns, Pondoland, South Africa, circa 1900; Territorial Studio (Umtata, South Africa); 1 photograph; 15 x 19.8 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts "Needles Hotel," a small wooden-framed building. Has, on the reverse, the ink stamp of the Territorial Studio (Umtata).
      South Africa; Photographs; Port Saint Johns (South Africa)
    - Port St. Johns, Pondoland, circa 1900; Territorial Studio (Umtata, South Africa); 1 photograph; 14.5 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts a small set of buildings at the base of a large, craggy, hillside. Several people stand in a lawn or open space to the front of the buildings. Has, on the reverse, the ink stamp of the Territorial Studio (Umtata).
      Port Saint Johns (South Africa); South Africa; Photographs
    - River ferry, South Africa, circa 1900; Territorial Studio (Umtata, South Africa); 1 photograph; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts a group of people moving across a river or lake on a ferry moved by ropes strung across the water. Has, on the reverse, the ink stamp of the Territorial Studio (Umtata).
    - General view of Grahamstown, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 19 x 25 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      A view of the town of Grahamstown/Grahamstad, South Africa. The town appears at some distance, beyond a fenced in field in the foreground and a dirt road on which two people walk at right.
      Grahamstown (South Africa); South Africa; Photographs
    - Cango Caves Exterior, Prince Albert, Oudtshoorn, circa 1900; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851-1950; 1 photograph; 21.5 x 27.5cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts the exterior of the Cango Caves in Oudtshoorn, South Africa. Eight people stand in front--a group of men and boys, wearing Western garb and appearing to be tourists at the cave. Has the ink stamp of "T.D. Ravenscroft" of Rondebosch (Cape Town), on the reverse
      Cango Caves (South Africa); Photographs; South Africa
    - Adderley Street, Cape Town, circa 1900; Sallo Epstein & Co.; 1 photograph; 15 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts a busy street in Cape Town, with numerous buggies and trolleys, and showing a large building with a sign reading "J.D. Cartwright and Co." Has ink stamp of "Sallo Epstein & Co." on the reverse.
      Cape Town (South Africa); South Africa; Photographs
    - Beach Promenade, Durban, South Africa, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Depicts a broad paved waterfront promenade in Durban. Several people are walking up and down the promenade or lounging on the lawns. Has ink stamp of "Sallo Epstein & Co." on the reverse.
      South Africa; Photographs; Durban (South Africa)
    - Lower Umkomaas, no. 94, circa 1900; Caney, E. E.; 1 photograph; 14.5 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      View of the Umkomaas (Mkomazi) River, spanned by a long low bridge. The photograph is signed E.E. Caney.
      Photographs; South Africa; Mkomazi River (South Africa)
    - Rand Hotel, Umkomaas, circa 1900; Caney, E. E.; 1 photograph; 14 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      View of the Rand Hotel, with several people in front. One woman rides a horse side-saddle, and other people ride in buggies. The scene also depicts several servants wearing dark sashes. Signed, on front, by E.E. Caney.
      South Africa; Umkomaas (South Africa); Photographs
    - Ox-driven cart carrying brush, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Large mountains are in view. The scene is probably in South Africa.
      Photographs; South Africa
    - General View of Lovedale, 1890s; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21.5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Titled in graphite on reverse, along with number ("2645"); presumably, the scene is Lovedale, South Africa. Depicts a landscape with grass-roofed huts and large plants growing in foreground.
      Photographs; Lovedale (South Africa); South Africa
  - Venice, Italy
    - Venezia, Canal Grande, H. Ganger, 3057, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Souvenir photograph depicting a young man in a checked blazer and straw hat being helped into/out of a gondola on the Grand Canal of Venice. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
      Grand Canal (Venice, Italy); Venice (Italy); Photographs
    - Venezia, Facciata di S. Marco, dettaglio, 3016, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts Piazza San Marco in Venice. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
      Photographs; Piazza San Marco (Venice, Italy); Venice (Italy)
    - Venezia, Panorama da mare, 3003, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
      Venice (Italy); Photographs
    - Venezia, Piazza e Basilica di S. Marco, 3022, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 24 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts a man and woman feeding pigeons in the Piazza San Marco, in Venice. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
      Piazza San Marco (Venice, Italy); Photographs; Venice (Italy)
    - Venezia, Palazzo ducale da mare, 3010, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts the Doges' Palace, Venice. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
      Photographs; Venice (Italy); Palazzo ducale (Venice, Italy)
    - Venezia, Calle Moretti, 3142, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Photographs; Venice (Italy)
    - Venezia, Cortile del palazzo dei Dogi, 3025, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts the courtyard of the Doges' palace in Venice. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
    - Venezia, Porta della Carta (palazzo ducale), 3011, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 19.5 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts an entrance to the Doges' Palace. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
    - Venezia, Procuratie S. Cristofaro, 3139, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 24 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts a man on a gondola in front of the Procuracy of St. Christopher. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
    - Venezia, Ponte dei Sospiri, 3065, 1900; Neue Photographische Gesellschaft; 1 photograph; 24 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Depicts the "Bridge of Sighs," with two gondolas rowing underneath. Blind-stamped on front: "Neue Photographische Gesellschaft, A.G., Berlin-Steglitz, 1900."
  - Funchal, Madeira
    - Kildonan Castle (Ship) at port in Funchal, Madeira, circa 1900; Lomelino, Dionizio da Camara; 1 albumen print; 17 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Depicts the Kildonan Castle steam ship at port in Funchal, Madeira. The ship was built in 1899 and went on to have a significant role in transport of troops and others between the UK and South Africa during the early years of the 20th century. On the reverse is the ink stamp of Dionizio da Camara Lomelino, photographer at Funchal.
      Photographs; Madeira Islands; Funchal (Madeira Islands)
    - Madeira-Funchal, Fish-market, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17.5 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Depicts an open air fish market in a town square of Funchal.
      Funchal (Madeira Islands); Madeira Islands; Photographs
    - Funchal-Este, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Depicts Funchal from a hilltop.
    - Funchal, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      View of Funchal, as seen from a hilltop overlooking it.
    - Funchal (?), circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      View of part of an unidentified coastal town, probably Funchal.
      Landscape photographs; Photographs; Travel photography
  - Unidentified
    - Unidentified Asian dwelling with man and snow, circa 1880; 1 albumen print; 11.5 x 16.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Small house, perhaps Chinese, in snow.
      China; Albumen prints
    - Unidentified rocky shore, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.5 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Depicts an unidentified rocky shoreline, with a few building in the distance.
    - Unidentified brook, with bridge, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified brook, with rocks, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified brook, with rocks, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified coast, rocky cliffs, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.7 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified rocky shore and inlet, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.7 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified shore, with breaking waves, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified coastal scene, village and boats, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified rocky shore, with small boats pulled in aground, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Unidentified shore, with rocks in foreground, grounded boats seen across a small waterway, and two-storey homes built side by side in background. A low stone wall with a tall watchtower appears at right. Likely the same coastal location as in other images found in this group of landscape photographs.
    - Unidentified shoreline with beach-goers, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15.5 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified railroad station, hilly landscape, circa 1920; 1 photograph; 11.8 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Unidentified landscape, possibly American, with railcars bearing logs stopped at a station in a grassy, hilly area. The railcars are labeled "N.C.R.," which may stand for "Northern Central Railroad," operational in Pennsylvania and surrounding states in the 19th and 20th centuries. There are some buildings behind the station, in the background. All structures appear wooden, and are very simple in nature. No explicit indication of location for this photograph.
    - Unidentified coastal area, with hills and sea, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17 x 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship's captain (?) with sextant, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 17.5 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Albumen prints; Nautical Instruments; Portraits
    - Unidentified ship passengers on deck, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 17.5 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Unidentified men and women lounge on deck chairs on a ship. Blinds are drawn partially to prevent too much sun from getting to the passengers.
      Portraits; Albumen prints
    - Unidentified rocky shore, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified rocky shore, with five beachgoers, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified rocky beach, with three beachgoers, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 15 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified mountain pass, man standing on small bridge, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 17 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified hillside with church and buildings in valley, circa 1900; 1 albumen print; 15.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified man at seashore, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified hotel or buildings in grassy hills, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 12 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Oversize, Series III
  - British scenes, etc.
    - "Mammoth Post Card" showing Christ Church College, Oxford, circa 1900; London Stereoscopic Company; 1 postcard; 22.3 x 31 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      The postcard is not addressed.
      Postcards; Christ Church (University of Oxford)
    - Harrow Road School portrait, young boys, 1897; 1 albumen print; 25 x 31 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      Portrait of thirty young schoolboys with their teacher, who stands at the back of the group. There is a small marquee on which is chalked "Harrow Road, II," perhaps indicating second year students. The boys appear to be about six or seven years of age. Print is mounted on a decorative card with information about the Royal family printed on it and a celebratory message: "1837 Sixty Years Happy and Glorious Reign 1897."
    - Harrow Road School portrait, older boys, 1897; 1 albumen print; 25 x 31 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      Portrait of a class of boys aged roughly twelve or thirteen. Their teacher stands to the left of the group. All boys wear suits, not uniforms, and several have academic medals pinned to their jackets. A small marquee has "Harrow Road [?]" chalked on it. Print is mounted on a decorative card with information about the Royal family printed on it and a celebratory message: "1837 Sixty Years Happy and Glorious Reign 1897."
    - Harrow Road School portrait, girls, 1897; 1 albumen print; 25 x 31 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      School portrait of a group of girls aged about ten. The girls all wear what appear to be their best dresses, not uniforms. A female teacher sits in the middle of the group, and another woman stands at top right. Potted plants are placed around the front row of seated girls. Print is mounted on a decorative card with information about the Royal family, and a celebratory message: "1837 Sixty Years Happy and Glorious Reign 1897."
    - Portrait of the "crew of the S Y [Royal Mersey Steam Yacht] Argo," June 1886., 1886 June; 1 albumen print; 26.5 x 34.5 (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      Portrait of the crew shows assembled sailors and staff, including one or two chefs and two women who look to be either nurses or maids. "The Argo," a steam yacht appears to have been instrumental in scientific expeditions in the 1870s through the 1890s. It is referenced in the title of Henry Hugh Higgins's 1877 book, "Notes by a Field-Naturalist in the Western Tropics: From a Journal Kept on Board the Royal Mersey Steam Yacht, 'The Argo.'" A small graphite sketch appears on the mounting card. It shows a view of a bay edged by mountains. It is labeled, in pen and ink, "Getting towards Kingstown Sugarloaf Mountain, June 6."
      Portraits; Albumen prints; Graphite drawings; Jamaica
    - Drawing Room at Melton Mowbray / Morning in India, 1880s or 1890s; 2 albumen prints, mounted on opposite sides of a card; 25.5 x 32.5 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      Photo on the front is labeled in pen and ink, "Drawing Room at Melton Mowbray." It depicts a large Victorian drawing room, heavily furnished and decorated. Several framed paintings and mirrors hang on the walls, and many ornaments adorn surfaces around the room. A woman sits reading a newspaper and a large dog sleeps at her feet. Another woman knits.
      Photo on the reverse is labeled, in pen and ink, "Morning in India." It depicts a brushy hill seen from a distance, with dense scrubby brush growing in the foreground.
      India; Albumen prints; Interior decoration -- Great Britain; Upholstery -- Great Britain
    - Church of St. Thomas of Canterbury, Whichelsea, 5th September 1895 / Eastbourne Regatta Day, 9th September 1895, 1895 September; 2 albumen prints mounted on a card; 24 x 28 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      The photo on the front depicts the Church of St. Thomas of Canterbury, clad in heavy ivy.
      The photo on the reverse depicts Eastbourne Regatta Day (rowing). The image shows large crowds at water's edge, awaiting the regatta.
      Albumen prints; Rowing
    - Mercery Lane, Canterbury, 7th September 1894 / Entrance gate, Canterbury Cathedral, and Marlow's monument, 7th Sept 1894, 1894 September; 2 photographs mounted on either side of a card; 24 x 27.5 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      First image shows a street with shops along it leading into a small stone-paved lane. The shops' windows show an impressive selection of silver goods at "Fox and Trimnell" and a dress for sale at "E. & E. LeFevre Ladies and Childrens' Outfitters."
      Second image shows a street view of Canterbury, with a portion of the Cathedral between what appear to be modern, nineteenth century buildings.
      Canterbury Cathedral; Canterbury (England); Photographs
    - Unidentified beach, with many small boats and bathers, circa 1900; 1 photograph; 16.5 x 38 cm (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    - Four unidentified landscape photographs, circa 1900; 4 photographs mounted on a heavy cardboard sheet; 16 x 12 cm (1 photo) and 12 x 16 cm (3 photos) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      All four photographs depict water features in a hilly terrain.
  - Maori portraits and Mariannhill Monastery
    - Paul Paora Tuhaere, Chief Orakie / Queen Aotea, Second Wife of King Tawhiao, 1880s; Pulman and Son Photographers; 2 albumen prints, mounted on opposite sides of a black paper sheet; 28 x 22 cm (Chief) 28 x 21 cm (Queen) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      Bust-length portrait of Paul Paora Tuhaere, a Maori Chief in Auckland, New Zealand. Portrait shows the chief wearing Western-style suit with white bibbed shirt and bow tie. He has a short white beard and mustache, and his tribal facial tattoos can be seen clearly.
      On the reverse is a portrait of Queen Aotea. She has short, dark, hair, and wears a traditional cloak with frilled collar and a feather in her hair. She has facial tattoos on her chin.
      Both images are signed Pulman Photo.
      Albumen prints; Portraits; New Zealand; Maori (New Zealand people) -- Portraits; Aotea, Queen, Second wife of King Tawhiao; Tuhaere, Paora, circa 1825-1892
    - Portrait of Wiremu and Rangitoia / Portrait of Tāwhiao, Maori King, 1880s; Pulman and Son Photographers; 2 albumen prints mounted on either side of a black paper sheet; 27.5 x 21 cm (both images) (Box Oversize 1, Folder 2)